Hello and welcome to the English we speak, where we explain phrases used by fluent English speakers
so that you can use them too. I'm Feifei.
And I'm Phil. How?
Ooh, you look like you're in painful. Are you okay?
I'll be okay. I hurt myself playing football, but I'm sure I can tough it out.
Tough it out. Are you sure you can, Phil?
Anyway, that's a great phrase to learn. What does tough it out mean?
If you tough it out, then you work through a painful or difficult situation.
You stay strong and don't change your plans.
And it's not just for physical pains like yours.
We can use it for difficult situations.
For example, you might be working for a company that can't afford to employ enough people
and you just have to tough it out until they've got some more money.
Let's hear some other people using this phrase.
I am so hungry.
I didn't have any time for breakfast, but I'm going to have to tough it out until my lunch break.
Oh no, there's no hot water and I really need a shower.
I'm going to have to tough it out.
Oh, there's no air conditioning in this building. I'm absolutely boiling.
I guess I'll just have to tough it out.
We've been learning the phrase tough it out to mean work through a difficult situation
and not let it stop you.
As a phrase, we always put it in the middle between tough and out.
Now, it originally comes from the phrasal verb tough something out and you can tough something out or tough out something.
Yes, it can be hard to learn phrasal verbs, but if you tough it out, you'll get there.
And make sure you come back for the next program. We'll see you then.
Bye-bye.
Bye.
Get the ultimate podcast experience on our website.
Find transcripts and subtitles to help you understand.
Try worksheets and quizzes to test what you've learned and use our handy vocabulary lists to help you study.
Plus, find video series like the London to Edinburgh Challenge and the pronunciation lounge to improve your English skills.
It's all available at BBCLearningEnglish.com.